interwetten7.com 2014-03-27

# Interwetten

| 

**1\. General Information**

Protecting players' personal data to the maximum extent possible is very important to Interwetten. The recording, processing and use of players' data are carried out strictly in accordance with the effective regulations for data protection.   
Interwetten Gaming Ltd (hereinafter "Interwetten"), the operator of [ www.interwetten.com](http://www.interwetten.com/), and Eurotrade International Ltd, the operator of [ www.iwfriends.com](http://www.iwfriends.com/), have been notified as data processors to the Office of the Commissioner for Data Protection in Malta. 

By providing Interwetten with his personal data, the player (hereinafter referred to as a neutral term and applicable to both sexes) confirms his consent to the processing of his personal information in line with this Data Protection Policy and the applicable data protection law (Chapter 440 of the Laws of Malta). Hence, the player explicitly authorizes Interwetten to process, utilize and make the information provided available to third parties in accordance with this Data Protection Policy. 

**2\. Data Collected Upon Upload**

When loading the website, servers will record the IP address of the requesting computer, the date and the time, the operating system, as well as the browser used by the player.   
Recording is necessary in order to enable use of the site by the player and in order to identify dysfunctions and abuse of the Interwetten offering. 

**3\. Data Collected Upon Registration**

Each player requesting access to the services offered by Interwetten (sports bets, virtual football, supertoto and superscore, casino, live casino, skill games, games and scratch-cards) has to open a customer account with Interwetten and register. 

During registration, the following data will need to be recorded: 

\- First name and last name   
\- Gender   
\- Complete address   
\- Date of Birth   
\- A verifiable email address   
\- Username and password   
\- Personal security question and answer 

Interwetten is obliged by law to verify the correctness of the data provided. Therefore, players may be requested - at any given time and in line with the applicable laws and regulations - to submit further documents to verify their identity and to enable security identity checks, such as 

a) a copy of a valid ID issued by the competent authority of a recognised state, e.g. passport, personal identity card, driver's license. In order to verify the player's identity even a utility bill (e.g. for gas, electricity or a lease contract) may be requested; 

b) a copy of each credit card (front and back) used for depositing into the player's Interwetten account as well as a copy of the credit card statements. 

Interwetten reserves the right to retain any winnings until the required documents are submitted. 

If players opt for depositing funds into the Interwetten account by credit card, the following additional personal data is required:   
\- Name and surname of cardholder   
\- Name of credit card company   
\- Credit card number   
\- Expiry date of credit card, CVC code and password 

For a transfer of winnings into the player's bank account, the following personal data has to be recorded: 

\- Name and surname of account holder   
\- Name of bank   
\- IBAN   
\- SWIFT code 

All information provided by the player for the records of Interwetten must be correct and complete. The player undertakes to notify Interwetten without delay in the event that any information provided has become incorrect or incomplete. Interwetten reserves the right to cancel any bets and winnings, block betting accounts, exclude the player from participating in games, and withhold payments to the player, if any information recorded by the player turns out to be incorrect or incomplete. The player is liable for any damages and costs arising out of false or misleading information. If false or misleading information is provided willfully, any and all transactions on the betting account shall be declared invalid. 

**4\. Data Collected When Using Interwetten Services**

**Profile**

Interwetten stores information that is collected by cookies, logfiles, clear gifs, and/or by third parties' support in order to create player profiles. A profile contains recorded information on individual players with exact indications of preferences concerning downloaded content. Logically, this information is related to the players' personal and identifiable data and used to provide offers and improvements in website content to the benefit of all players. Profiles are used to design each player's experience on the Interwetten website individually and to provide specific marketing information. 

**Cookies**

A cookie is a piece of data saved on the player's computer and linked to specific user information. The use of cookies is not related with any personally identifiable information while players visit our site. Interwetten uses session ID cookies as well as persistent cookies. Session ID cookies will be deleted once the player closes the browser. A persistent cookie represents a small text file saved on the player's hard drive for an extended period of time. 

Most internet browsers accept cookies on a standard basis. Players may deactivate the use of cookies in their security settings. 

**Logfiles**

Interwetten uses logfiles. These include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp and the number of clicks to analyze trends for administration of the site, to track players' movements on the site, and to gather usable comprehensive demographic information. IP addresses are related to the provision of web-based services with personally identifiable information. 

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**

Some of our marketing partners use a software technology called 'clear gifs' (also known as Web Beacons/Web Bugs) that helps us to manage content on our site better by indicating the effectiveness of specific content. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier. They are similar in function to cookies and used to track the online movements of web users. The main difference between a cookie and a clear gifs lies in the fact that clear gifs are visible on the page. Clear gifs are not linked to players' personally identifiable information. Together with cookies, clear gifs may be utilized to identify previous online behavior of a specific computer's user. Such information may be made available to specific marketing partners on a case-by-case basis. 

**5\. Use of Personal Data**

The recording of personal data is carried out in order to verify the identity and age of players process the contractual arrangement between Interwetten and the player communicate with the player fulfill legal obligations, in particular the matching of player data with national and international player protection databases (self-exclusion lists). 

**6\. Disclosure of Personal Data**

Player data is treated in strict confidence. 

As a matter of principle, personal player data will not be disclosed to third parties unless such disclosure occurs on the basis of legal obligations or rights, or unless such disclosure has been authorized by the player. 

On a case-by-case basis, Interwetten makes use of services provided by third parties acting in the company's name. These third parties are obliged to treat players' data securely and confidentially. Their use of said data is restricted to the extent required to fulfil the respective task. Therefore, only the required minimum of data will be provided. 

In order to complete players' identity verification, player data may be matched against the databases of the international GB Group Ltd. 

Upon any indication of transactions and/or activities that may raise suspicions of criminal activities, Interwetten will report to the relevant parties in charge (e.g. police, sporting associations, private associations aiming at the prevention of criminal and fraudulent activities in sports betting and/or games of chance). 

In this context, personal data may also be transferred in the framework of an early warning system to the European Sports Security Association (ESSA) and the respective sports federations. With the acceptance of the General Terms and Conditions and this Data Protection Policy, the player grants his explicit consent to this procedure. 

Furthermore, Interwetten reserves the right to record telephone calls with players and forward recordings to law enforcement agencies if there is precise evidence of criminal offences. 

The player's acceptance of this Data Protection Policy authorizes Interwetten to conduct the above-mentioned security checks, including requests for credit information and the matching of data provided against databases of third parties. 

Insofar as Interwetten may make use of external providers in order to carry out and administer data processing services, the contractual arrangements will comprehend and strictly comply with the applicable data protection regulations.

Interwetten's commitment to the protection of personal data notwithstanding, the company reserves the right to publish gaming data (e.g. achieved results), the player's first name, the initial of the surname as well as the player's country of residence on the Interwetten website as long as the player remains, directly and indirectly, unidentifiable. 

**7\. Saved Data**

Whenever a player closes his Interwetten account, the personal data saved in the system will remain stored for a period of usually seven years, commencing from the date of the closure, in compliance with the applicable regulations. 

**8\. Data Security**

All data will be processed in an automated manner.   
Interwetten takes all adequate precautions in order to protect players' data. In particular payment information will always be encrypted when data is being processed. 

Whereas sensitive information is protected online by SSL encryption, Interwetten makes any reasonable effort to ensure the protection of players' data in all other areas, too. 

Only authorized employees of Interwetten, or employees of third parties contractually bound to compliance with the principles of data protection, have access to players' information. 

Interwetten monitors the trustworthiness and reliability of all its employees. One fundamental workplace rule enforces the use of password-protected screensavers whenever the workplace remains unattended. At regular intervals, all employees are given training on the applicable security and data protection standards. All employees are informed about their legal obligations, either annually or upon current changes. The significance of regulations concerning data protection and the importance of everybody's personal contribution is at the centre of all training programmes. All relevant servers are located in a secure environment. 

**Data Encryption**

In order to protect players' personal data during communication with the web browser, Interwetten uses encryption technology of its certification partner Thawte. In addition, online transactions are shielded by the security system of a worldwide-accredited partner. 

**Other Technical Security Measures**

With the aim of preventing illegal manipulation by third parties, the computer's IP address will be requested and saved when the player logs in. In addition, all player data is protected from unauthorized access by firewall and intrusion prevention systems. 

**9\. Change of Personal Data**

Following login, players may change their personal data at any time under "Change account data" on the Interwetten homepage [ www.interwetten.com](http://www.interwetten.com/)   
(with the exception of the surname, first name, date of birth, country, and user name and nickname). Every player is obliged by law to update his personal data without delay once information provided to Interwetten is no longer correct or is incomplete. 

**10\. Players' Rights**

Under the data protection regulations all players have the right to demand access to the data saved and processed in their name by Interwetten. They are also entitled to request rectification, the deletion or barring of data in accordance with the laws on data protection. 

For questions concerning this Data Protection Policy or concerning the safety of data provided to Interwetten, players may contact the service department by email [ service@interwetten.com](mailto:service@interwetten.com) at any time. 

This Data Protection Policy is set forth in several different languages. In the event of discrepancies or disputes between different language versions, the English text prevails. 

**11\. Amendments to the Data Protection Policy**

This Data Protection Policy is subject to change at any time. Although players will always be informed about any changes, it is recommended to review this policy and potential amendments regularly. 

Version 1.2 – last update on 13.01.2014 

References:   
Maltese Data Protection Act 2001, amended by law XVI and XXV; English language version may be uploaded at [ http://idpc.gov.mt/dbfile.aspx/DPA_amended2012.pdf](http://idpc.gov.mt/dbfile.aspx/DPA_amended2012.pdf). 

Top of page  
  
---|---
